Stephen Kohlmann

Full Stack Developer

I'm a driven and skilled professional in multiple disciplines and industries. As a recent masters graduate I would like to further my career as a web developer. I am passionate about technology and would like to build upon my experience from UCD and remote role with Apple. My ideal role would involve blending my computer science skills with my passion for creativity and design.



stephen.kohlmann@gmail.com

086 050 7732



Sligo, Ireland

WORK EXPERIENCE

Lecturer in Computer Science Griffith College Dublin 🗷

01/2018 - Present

Tasks/Contributions

- Task: Design and deliver undergraduate and postgraduate modules.
- Task: Designing in class test, labs, assignments and exams.
- Contribution: Helping students develop core computer science skills.

AHA - Technical Support - iOS/Mac **Apple**

07/2015 - Present

Tasks/Contributions

- Task: Technical phone support for the iOS and macOS platforms.
- Task: Deliver on multiple metric targets daily.
- Contributions: Lowest call handling time for all Mac advisors in 2017.

Demonstrator (SQL & Relational Databases) U.C.D

01/2016 - 05/2016

Tasks/Contributions

- Task: Guided students through SQL, PL/SQL code.
- Task: Guided students through relational database theory and concepts.
- Contribution: Corrected weekly labs, design documents and final project submissions.

Programming Teacher

Castlepark Park Primary School

01/2015 - 01/2016

Tasks/Contributions

- Task: Taught students programming via Scratch.
- Task: Taught students web programming via HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Contribution: Designed a teaching curriculum to introduce programming to primary school students.

EDUCATION

MSc. in Computer Science

U.C.D

09/2014 - 09/2016

HDip in Science and Computing

I.T Sligo 🛂

09/2013 - 09/2014

SKILLS

HTML

Bootstrap

MvSOL

Javascript

Python

Github

MongoDB

PERSONAL PROJECTS/LINKS

Portfolio 🛂

My portfolio website with relevant projects

GitHub 🗹

Personal Development Projects

Publication in Digital Forensics - ADFSL

HTML5 Zero Configuration Covert Channels: Security Risks and Challenges

LinkedIn 🗹

Full CV available here

CERTIFICATES

Build Websites From Scratch (10/2017 - 12/2017)

A 10 week curriculum of web development fundamentals using HTML, CSS, Javascript and Github

INTERESTS

Music

ITF Taekwon-Do

Computer Science